Hello friends, I am Dr. Ved Prakash
Mishra, welcome to my YouTube channel.
We started a process to find out
what are the treatments for piles?
We have uploaded many of its videos in sequence.
You will get information about each type of treatment separately in that video.
Today in this video I want to tell you
a very famous
process that
what is the operation of piles by stapler or telescope method
stapler?  A stapler is a machine.  One such
machine is known as stapler.  In
this, we empty it in the front part
and
it goes inside through the toilet.  Then we tighten it and
click it.  So what happens is
that the donut in the middle, the entire
part of the anal canal in which the pile mass is present
in the circular part, comes out and
both the ends of the anal canal become stable with each other.
So this is the stabler procedure or it is
said by the method of telescope that
operation of the piece by telescope, for its operation
we have to pay very special attention.
This method should always be used
by a skilled doctor who has
complete experience because even if there is a fire and there is
no staple, it can cause problems.  There is a
lot of bleeding later.
So to avoid these, always
choose a doctor who uses staples regularly.
One drawback of this is that
it is only for internal piles and
this machine is expensive, the price of one staple itself is
expensive and it is use and throw,
we cannot use it again.
Once used in a patient, it
cannot be used again.  So our
treatment cost increases.
What is good about this is that if there is a circular mass
then all the piles mass comes out together in a donut.
So we do not have to tamper with it again and again
and the entire ring
comes out together and becomes stable.  If this
process is done correctly then there is no
bleeding.  There is no pain
and the patient is able to go back to work within two to three days.
For any information regarding this, you can contact on the number given below.